

□ (+33)750858649 | ■ nguyentd@eurecom.fr | □ github.com/trungduynguyen | □ Duy Trung

"Seeking for a challenging and innovative position in Data Science. I am fascinated to shape and transform data to valuable knowledge."

## Summary\_

Current a data scientist Intern & a graduate student in Data Science with 2+ years experience specializing in backend/infrastructure, data analytics and machine learning. Looking for research jobs which fit my interests in these topics: Deep learning, Gaussian process and Bayesian analysis. Fascinated in exploring a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

### Education.

#### Institute Mines-Télécom(IMT)/EURÉCOM, campus SophiaTech

Biot, France

M.Sc in Data Science and Engineering

Sep. 2016 - Exp. Jan. 2018

· Courseworks: Deep Learning, Distributed System, Inferential Statistics

#### Ho Chi Minh University of Science (HCMUS) - Vietnam National University

Ho Chi Minh city, Vietnam

Sep. 2011 - Sep. 2015

B.S. in Computer Science

- Top 10 % students of Department of Information Technology
- Thesis: Transforming between C++ source code and UML models

# Wor**k Experience**\_\_\_\_\_

**KPMG Deutschland**Frankfurt, Germany

Data Scientist Intern - Supervisor: Prof. Pietro Michiardi

Aug. 2017 - PRESENT

- Build and deploy overall service infrastructure utilizing Docker containers or Kubernetes pods, focusing on high-availability, fault tolerance, and auto-scaling.
- Data cleansing and integration from multiple data sources
- Enhance the accuracy of Recommendation System for Solution Sales Engine: Collaborative Filtering
- Apply Deep Learning and Time-Series Forecasting techniques to detect sale patterns: Tensorflow, Keras, pandas, scipy, scikit-learn, mllib

EURECOM Biot, France

Research Assistant - Supervisor: Dr. Maurizio Filippone

Mar. 2017 - July. 2017

Sep. 2015 - Aug. 2016

- Constructed Ingredients parser based semantics
- Web-mining: Implemented web crawler to scrap food recipes: Scrappy, BeautifulSoup, Selenium
- · Text-retrieval and Natural Language Processing (NLP) tasks: Inverted list, TF-IDF, Indexing, Stemming, Tokenization
- · Implemented Recommendation system for food, classified food categories by KNN and Bayesian classifiers, Gaussian process

**Tenpoint7**Ho Chi Minh city, Vietnam

Data Analyst
Crawled data and developed immensely efficient data collection procedures.

- · Interpreted and analyzed results by conducting statistical measurements and providing ongoing reports
- Conducted several experiments with involving different kinds of supervised algorithms (Neural Network, Decision Tree, Naive Bayes Classifier)

#### Ho Chi Minh University of Science (HCMUS)

Ho Chi Minh city, Vietnam

• Guided students how to state hypotheses and tested them in scientific approaches

Oct. 2015 - Feb. 2016

- Gave tutorials to conduct scientific papers on Latex
- Attended to office hours weekly to ensure students understanding course concepts

**ToxTalent**Ho Chi Minh city, Vietnam

Data Analyst

**Teaching Assistant** 

Sep. 2013, Mar. 2011 - Oct. 2011

- Implemented knowledge crowd-sourcing system
- Collected/Analyzed user requirements, market research
- Designed mockups, constructed test-cases, quality assurance
- · Operated software development processes (SCRUM, Agile), planned strategies and prioritized tasks/resources for each Sprint

NOVEMBER 14, 2017 TRUNG-DUY NGUYEN · RÉSUMÉ 1

#### John von Neumann Institute - Vietnam National University (VNU)

Ho Chi Minh city, Vietnam

Jun. 2014 - Sep. 2014

- Research Assistant Supervisor: Prof. Vu N. Duong
- Built up an iOS application to collect user traffic pattern: Objective-C, MVC model
- Researched on Intelligence Transportation Systems (ITS) scientific papers and provided reports
- · Visualized personal traffic trajectories on GoogleMap
- · Simulated shortest pathways for each particular user

# Projects

2017	Datasets for	Machine	Learning	in the	kitchen
------	--------------	---------	----------	--------	---------

- 2017 Deep Learning: Lenet-5 Model for Optical Character Recognition on MNIST: Tensorflow
- 2017 Estimating Financial Risk through Monte Carlo Simulation
- 2017 Building a music recommender system: Collaborative-Filtering, Alternating Least Squares
- 2016 Sentiment Analysis on Yelp dataset
- 2015 Classification on Red wine dataset: Random Forest, Naive Bayes classifiers

### Awards & Certificates\_

- 2017 Neural Networks and Deep Learning Coursera's certificate
- Improving Deep Neural Networks: Hyperparameter tuning, Regularization and Optimization Coursera's 2017

certificate

- 2017 Structuring Machine Learning Projects Coursera's certificate
- 2016 **EURECOM scholarship for international students** cover all tuition fee
- 2015 Being A Leader and The Effective Exercise of Leadership John von Neumann Institute's certificate
- 2015 John von Neumann Institute Tenpoint7 partner scholarship fully financial aid

## References\_

Professor Vu N.DUONG Singapore

Director of Air Traffic Management Research Institute of Nanyang Technological University (NTU)

- Tel: (+65)6908 3412
- Email: VU.DUONG@NTU.EDU.SG

## Maurizio Filippone, PhD

Biot, France

AXA Chair of Computational Statistics and Assistant Professor at EURECOM

- Tel: (+33) 4 93 00 81 35
- Email: maurizio.filippone@eurecom.fr